TRIPTI WANI

Full Stack Web Developer

Telephone +61 481 254 765
Email tripti.895@gmail.com
Address Sydney, Australia
Website triptiwani.github.io

PROFILE

Focused and self-motivated professional, with 7 years experience in Information Technology. Aspiring full stack web developer with a strong interest in projects that require both conceptual and analytical thinking. I love to solve problems with code while applying industry best practices in a collaborative environment. Fully- committed to designing and developing innovative web-based materials that users will love. Always eager to learn more tricks from anyone - regardless of the industry they're working in.

Technical Skills

HTML CSS

Javascript Backbone.js

jQuery Ruby Underscore.js

Rails Database:

BootStrap SQL, Postgres

Github Ajax

TDD - Rspec,

RESTful APIs Cucumber

UNIX Scripting

Heroku

References

Joel Turnbull, Instructor,GA Bala R. , RXP Services Limited

Contact details are available on request

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

June 2016 - Aug 2016

General Assembly is a pioneer in education and career transformation, specialising in today's most in-demand skills.

TALK2ME

User friendly web-based chat application covering photos, gifs and location with a Mobile-first approach.

Tech Stack: HTML/CSS./javascript/jQuery,Ruby,Rails 5, Puma/Redis,Cloudinary/Bootstrap, Gifshot.js, GoogleMaps.js,jQueryAutoComplete.js

PALATE

A mobile-first app for creating, bookmarking and sharing recipes from any existing recipe websites via chrome extension.

Tech Stack:HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,RUBY /RAILS 4.2.6, Cloudinary/Bootstrap,Nokogiri,bcrypt,httparty,ratyrate,Chorme Dev tool, Padilicious.js

INVENOTRY MANAGEMENT

This is an e-commerce website to procure, track and deal in Mobile handsets and accessories for wholesalers and retailers across multiple locations with the built-in payment feature.

Tech Stack:HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby /Rails 4.2.6, Cloudinary/Sendgrid, Stripe.js, money-rails Twitter/Facebook/bcrypt

INFOSYS LIMITED

July 2008 - Sep 2015

Infosys Limited is an Indian multinational corporation that provides business consulting, information technology and outsourcing services.

Technology Lead/ Technology Analyst

July 2012 - Sep 2015

- Interactions with the business analysts for analysis and understanding of the technical requirements to be applied
- Performed Requirement Analysis, Design with Development and testing
- Contribution of functional and technical documents to the Knowledge Center
- Provide technical mentoring to the team members, perform reviews artifacts prior to delivery
- Handling Configuration Management and Control
- Worked on the ETL Framework migration

Senior Software Engineer/Software Engineer July 2008 - June 2012

- Creation of source code for conversion and collection programs
- Planning and tracking 24*7 production support cycle
- Respond to and fix production issues within acceptable timelines
- Conduct analysis, and suggest/implement work-around and perform Root Cause Analysis and fixes to avoid re-occurence.

HIGHLIGHT

SIGNMEUP - SheHacks2016 organised by GirlGeekSydney

Building a sign language translator app for people with hearing loss and received Third place.

http://site-55311-9163-8820.strikingly.com/

EDUCATION

2016 - 2016	Web Development Immersive
	General Assembly, Sydney
2011 - 2013	MBA in Human Resource
	Symbiosis, India
2004 - 2008	M.Sc. (Hons.) Chemistry – Integrated Course
	RITS Pilani, India